<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:24-29</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_24to29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_24to29/</guid>
      <description>Paul wrote the letter to the Colossians during his time in prison (4:3). He suffered much for the gospel (2 Cor 11:23–33). Yet here, Paul rejoices in his sufferings. Why? He rejoices because he sees his personal sufferings in the context of the cosmic plan of God to reconcile all things to himself through Jesus (1:20, 25).
This plan was formerly a mystery (1:26), but was revealed to the saints when Jesus came, died, rose, and sent the Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:21-23</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</guid>
      <description>In the Colossian Hymn (1:15–20), Paul zooms out to see the whole universe of Jesus’s reconciling work. Paul now zooms in to examine the impact of that work on the Colossian believers (and us). He begins with our former state: “alienated and hostile in mind.” Because of the fall, this is the starting point for all human beings. We are all alienated from God by sin. Not only are we alienated, but we are hostile towards God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:15–20</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</guid>
      <description>Colossians 1:15–20 is probably the most well-known section of Paul’s letter. Called the Colossian Hymn, this paragraph forms a three-verse hymn echoing the refrain of Christ’s preeminence.
The first verse of the hymn exalts Jesus as the firstborn of the first creation. He is the image of the invisible God and shows us perfectly what our first parents were supposed to be. When God said, “let us make man in our image,” Jesus was the template (Gen 1:26).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 04 - Service &amp; Streets</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170604/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:07:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170604/</guid>
      <description>Today was our first full day in Dublin. And it was full indeed. I got my first taste of Irish breakfast at the hotel (bangers, beans, bacon, tomatoes, blood sausage, egg). Then we departed for church service. My group attended City Church Dublin just across the River Liffey from our hotel. We sang together and Pastor Mark preached from Acts 21. City Church Dublin is a small church plant in the heart of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 03 - Travel</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170603/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 22:21:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170603/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we departed for Ireland. We met at the airport at 7pm and Pastors David Livingston and Daniel Viezbicke exhorted us from the word and prayed for us. Saying goodbye to family was difficult. The kids handled it pretty well (though Ruby pointed out that we could have sprung to bring a few more kiddos with on the trip). The flight was good. This was my first time flying international. &amp;ldquo;Waking up&amp;rdquo; after only a few hours of sleep and finding out I lost seven hours by crossing time zones was very surreal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:9–14</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you asked someone, “How can I pray for you?” Or how often have you promised to pray and then found yourself unsure of what to pray for? As we meet many in need of prayer in Ireland, what should we pray? In Colossians 1:9–14, Paul shares some of his priorities for prayer for the Colossian church. We can learn how to pray for one another by thinking about Paul’s priorities in prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:1–8</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 18:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</guid>
      <description>Paul begins his letter to the church at Colossae by expressing his thankfulness for their strong faith and abundant love. Paul says this faith and love is “because of the hope laid up for you in heaven” (1:5). What kind of hope could be strong enough to sustain faith in a world marked by suffering? What kind of hope could be strong enough to promote love among sinful people? Paul writes that it is gospel hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Trip Route</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 19:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</guid>
      <description>Above is a map of our route in Ireland. We will be in Dublin June 3-6, Kilkeel June 6-8, Belfast June 8-10, Derry &amp;amp; Buncrana June 10-13, then back to Dublin June 13-15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:07:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</guid>
      <description>God graciously provided 100% of the funds needed for this trip through the gifts of many friends and family. Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support at 80%!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:46:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</guid>
      <description>After posting online, God used the generosity of donors to bring my funding for Ireland from 45% to 80% in a matter of days. I am so very grateful to all who have donated and all who are praying for the rest of the funds to come in and for the trip to have success.
I have also made some good contacts in Ireland and have a better idea of when and where I will be meeting with folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Update - April</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 17:42:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the generosity of many people, I&amp;rsquo;m 45.86% funded! Praise the Lord for his goodness. Will you join me in praying for God to provide the $2,003 still needed?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>