<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ireland Trip Log on The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/series/ireland-trip-log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ireland Trip Log on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 10:05:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/series/ireland-trip-log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Trip Reflections</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/ireland-trip-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 10:05:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/ireland-trip-reflections/</guid>
      <description>The pictures below represent the folks I talked with while I was in Ireland. Karl, Luke, Chuck, and Zack came on the trip with us from home. We had many good conversations (Zack was also my room mate for much of the trip). Samuel and Zak are part of the Eden Gate Travel team. David was our trip photographer. Kieron and Mark are pastors in Dublin. Lucas and Andrew are pastors in Belfast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 12-14 - Dublin Again and Home</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170613/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:51:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170613/</guid>
      <description>The morning of June 13th, we left Buncrana to travel back to Dublin. By this time in the trip, I was beginning to get sick. Unfortunately, most of the rest of our time in Dublin I was sick and exhausted. This trip was very busy and full.
I managed to meet with Kieron one more time in Dublin and he gave me some excellent questions to consider in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 12 - Amazing Grace</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170612/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 09:22:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170612/</guid>
      <description>This morning, we walked back down to the Amazing Grace Viewing Point on Lough Swilly. This lough plays a significant role in the story of John Newton and Amazing Grace. Ruth and Andrew Garvey-Williams have worked hard to highlight this story in the community. You can read more about their work and the story of Amazing Grace here. We came to the viewing point to get some more footage singing Amazing Grace in Irish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 11 - Sunday in Buncrana</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170611/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 08:45:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170611/</guid>
      <description>Today is Sunday. While the choir left to sing at St. Columb&amp;rsquo;s Cathedral, I stayed at the hotel and worked on my sermon for this evening. Our hotel was inside the city walls near a memorial in the center of the old city. While working on my sermon, I heard music coming from the square. It seems there was some kind of memorial service that morning. I enjoyed listening to it while I finished sermon prep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 10 - Antrim Coast to Derry</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 16:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170610/</guid>
      <description>This morning, we left Belfast for Derry. We took the Antrim Coast road, which goes along the northern coast of Ireland. All of Ireland is beautiful, but this part is superlatively beautiful. The landscape along the coast is what most of us picture when think of Ireland.
First we stopped in Larne and sang Amazing Grace around an Irish flag for a drone shot. Then we drove further up the coast and stopped above the Carrick-a-Rede Rope Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 08 &amp; 09 - Traveling &amp; Belfast</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170608/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 07:57:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170608/</guid>
      <description>This morning we left beautiful Kilkeel and continued our trek up the eastern coast of Ireland. We took the scenic route to Belfast to take in some of the scenery and history of this part of Ireland.
We visited Saul church, the traditional landing site of Saint Patrick in Ireland in the 5th century. The building and area was serene.
Then we took a ferry across the mouth of the Strangford Lough and stopped at Harrisons of Greyabbey for lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 07 - Atticall Chapel</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170607/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:03:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170607/</guid>
      <description>Today was our first morning in Kilkeel. Kilkeel is a small fishing town right on the edge of the Irish Sea. Thus, I knew I wanted to get up early and catch a sunrise. According to google, the sunrise in Kilkeel comes at 4:53 AM. Ouch! Ireland is +6 hrs from Minnesota, so that’s 10:53 PM my time. Still, I made it up and walked 1&amp;frasl;2 a mile or so to the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 06 - Saint Patrick&#39;s Cathedral</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170606/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 20:35:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170606/</guid>
      <description>Today was our last day in Dublin this side of the trip. We will return for a few days at the end of the trip before we fly home.
We made the most of our time with a very full day. After loading up our luggage, we walked to Saint Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Cathedral to attend a vespers service. The service was very “high church”—beautiful, but difficult to understand. After the vespers service, I met for coffee with Mark Smith, pastor of City Church Dublin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 05 - Christ Church Cathedral</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170605/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 14:07:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170605/</guid>
      <description>Today, the choir sang in Christ Church Cathedral. The cathedral is straight across the street from our hotel and is a beautiful and historic building. The choir sang well and the performance was well received. The cathedral is a reverent place, so songs like O Nata Lux were especially beautiful in that context. After singing in the cathedral, we participated in a tour. During the tour, we climbed 800 year old stairs to get to the bell tower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 04 - Service &amp; Streets</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170604/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:07:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170604/</guid>
      <description>Today was our first full day in Dublin. And it was full indeed. I got my first taste of Irish breakfast at the hotel (bangers, beans, bacon, tomatoes, blood sausage, egg). Then we departed for church service. My group attended City Church Dublin just across the River Liffey from our hotel. We sang together and Pastor Mark preached from Acts 21. City Church Dublin is a small church plant in the heart of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Log - June 03 - Travel</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170603/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 22:21:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-log-20170603/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we departed for Ireland. We met at the airport at 7pm and Pastors David Livingston and Daniel Viezbicke exhorted us from the word and prayed for us. Saying goodbye to family was difficult. The kids handled it pretty well (though Ruby pointed out that we could have sprung to bring a few more kiddos with on the trip). The flight was good. This was my first time flying international. &amp;ldquo;Waking up&amp;rdquo; after only a few hours of sleep and finding out I lost seven hours by crossing time zones was very surreal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Trip Route</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 19:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</guid>
      <description>Above is a map of our route in Ireland. We will be in Dublin June 3-6, Kilkeel June 6-8, Belfast June 8-10, Derry &amp;amp; Buncrana June 10-13, then back to Dublin June 13-15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:07:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</guid>
      <description>God graciously provided 100% of the funds needed for this trip through the gifts of many friends and family. Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support at 80%!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:46:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</guid>
      <description>After posting online, God used the generosity of donors to bring my funding for Ireland from 45% to 80% in a matter of days. I am so very grateful to all who have donated and all who are praying for the rest of the funds to come in and for the trip to have success.
I have also made some good contacts in Ireland and have a better idea of when and where I will be meeting with folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Update - April</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 17:42:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the generosity of many people, I&amp;rsquo;m 45.86% funded! Praise the Lord for his goodness. Will you join me in praying for God to provide the $2,003 still needed?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>