<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colossians Devotional on The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/series/colossians-devotional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colossians Devotional on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/series/colossians-devotional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:21-23</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</guid>
      <description>In the Colossian Hymn (1:15–20), Paul zooms out to see the whole universe of Jesus’s reconciling work. Paul now zooms in to examine the impact of that work on the Colossian believers (and us). He begins with our former state: “alienated and hostile in mind.” Because of the fall, this is the starting point for all human beings. We are all alienated from God by sin. Not only are we alienated, but we are hostile towards God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:15–20</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</guid>
      <description>Colossians 1:15–20 is probably the most well-known section of Paul’s letter. Called the Colossian Hymn, this paragraph forms a three-verse hymn echoing the refrain of Christ’s preeminence.
The first verse of the hymn exalts Jesus as the firstborn of the first creation. He is the image of the invisible God and shows us perfectly what our first parents were supposed to be. When God said, “let us make man in our image,” Jesus was the template (Gen 1:26).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:9–14</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you asked someone, “How can I pray for you?” Or how often have you promised to pray and then found yourself unsure of what to pray for? As we meet many in need of prayer in Ireland, what should we pray? In Colossians 1:9–14, Paul shares some of his priorities for prayer for the Colossian church. We can learn how to pray for one another by thinking about Paul’s priorities in prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:1–8</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 18:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</guid>
      <description>Paul begins his letter to the church at Colossae by expressing his thankfulness for their strong faith and abundant love. Paul says this faith and love is “because of the hope laid up for you in heaven” (1:5). What kind of hope could be strong enough to sustain faith in a world marked by suffering? What kind of hope could be strong enough to promote love among sinful people? Paul writes that it is gospel hope.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>