<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colossians Devotional on The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/series/colossians-devotional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colossians Devotional on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/series/colossians-devotional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 3:12-17</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_12to17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_12to17/</guid>
      <description>Finished with the old nature, Paul flips the coin over and examines our new nature in Christ Jesus. Love for one another and submission to Christ&amp;rsquo;s lordship characterizes this new nature.
Paul calls the Colossians to put on the new nature. The virtues he lists are not unique to Christianity. People can be compassionate, kind, and so on, without loving Jesus. What is unique about this list is the modifiers. The saints are to put on “as God’s chosen ones, holy and beloved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 3:5-11</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_5to11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_5to11/</guid>
      <description>Paul shifts his gaze from looking to heaven to looking to earth. Here he explains to the Colossians how a life hid with Christ in God works while still here on earth. Paul begins with three negative imperatives: 1) put to death, 2) put away, and 3) do not lie.
Paired with the first two imperatives, Paul provides two lists of sins. At first glance the lists may seem arbitrary, but they are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 3:1-4</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_1to4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col3_1to4/</guid>
      <description>In Colossians 3, Paul shifts his focus from the shadows of the earthly false teachers to the reality of the risen Christ. “If then you have been raised with Christ,” (3:1) parallels his statement in Colossians 2:20: “If with Christ you died.” Paul asserts both are true for the Colossian believers and the statements that follow unpack this significance. Since the believers in Colossae have been raised with Christ, their focus should be heavenward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 2:16-23</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_16to23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_16to23/</guid>
      <description>All who love Jesus want to obey God’s commandments and grow in holiness and wisdom. This is what made the false teachers in Colossae so dangerous. They promised 10 Steps to Fulfill the Ten Commandments. They advertised secret knowledge from spirits and visions. They promised their rules could restrain the unruly flesh. The false teachers sold snake oil—they held out the hope of life, but it was a lie. In Colossians 2:16–23, Paul exposes the false hope of the false teachers by pointing to the true hope in Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 2:6-15</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_6to15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_6to15/</guid>
      <description>Colossians 2:6–7 is the main thesis in Colossians. Here, Paul has arrived at his purpose for writing. The main point is this: continue to hope in Christ, for he is supreme and sufficient.
In the first part of the letter, Paul points believers back to how they received Christ (1:5–7, 23, 2:5). He does this to build their confidence in “the faith” they received. In saying, &amp;ldquo;walk in him,&amp;rdquo; Paul is assuring them they are on the right path to salvation and glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 2:1–5</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_1to5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col2_1to5/</guid>
      <description>Paul here relates his suffering and toil directly to the lives of the Colossian believers. Paul is not looking for sympathy or pity, but is telling his story “that [your] hearts may be encouraged” (2:2). This seems counter-intuitive. Many of us have experienced someone telling us how hard they worked for our benefit. Those of us who are parents have probably told our kids how great our struggle was on their behalf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:24-29</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_24to29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_24to29/</guid>
      <description>Paul wrote the letter to the Colossians during his time in prison (4:3). He suffered much for the gospel (2 Cor 11:23–33). Yet here, Paul rejoices in his sufferings. Why? He rejoices because he sees his personal sufferings in the context of the cosmic plan of God to reconcile all things to himself through Jesus (1:20, 25).
This plan was formerly a mystery (1:26), but was revealed to the saints when Jesus came, died, rose, and sent the Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:21-23</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_21to23/</guid>
      <description>In the Colossian Hymn (1:15–20), Paul zooms out to see the whole universe of Jesus’s reconciling work. Paul now zooms in to examine the impact of that work on the Colossian believers (and us). He begins with our former state: “alienated and hostile in mind.” Because of the fall, this is the starting point for all human beings. We are all alienated from God by sin. Not only are we alienated, but we are hostile towards God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:15–20</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_15to20/</guid>
      <description>Colossians 1:15–20 is probably the most well-known section of Paul’s letter. Called the Colossian Hymn, this paragraph forms a three-verse hymn echoing the refrain of Christ’s preeminence.
The first verse of the hymn exalts Jesus as the firstborn of the first creation. He is the image of the invisible God and shows us perfectly what our first parents were supposed to be. When God said, “let us make man in our image,” Jesus was the template (Gen 1:26).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:9–14</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_9to14/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you asked someone, “How can I pray for you?” Or how often have you promised to pray and then found yourself unsure of what to pray for? As we meet many in need of prayer in Ireland, what should we pray? In Colossians 1:9–14, Paul shares some of his priorities for prayer for the Colossian church. We can learn how to pray for one another by thinking about Paul’s priorities in prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colossians 1:1–8</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 18:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/col1_1to8/</guid>
      <description>Paul begins his letter to the church at Colossae by expressing his thankfulness for their strong faith and abundant love. Paul says this faith and love is “because of the hope laid up for you in heaven” (1:5). What kind of hope could be strong enough to sustain faith in a world marked by suffering? What kind of hope could be strong enough to promote love among sinful people? Paul writes that it is gospel hope.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>