<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 19:11:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Trip Route</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 19:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/trip-route/</guid>
      <description>Above is a map of our route in Ireland. We will be in Dublin June 3-6, Kilkeel June 6-8, Belfast June 8-10, Derry &amp;amp; Buncrana June 10-13, then back to Dublin June 13-15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:07:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-funded/</guid>
      <description>God graciously provided 100% of the funds needed for this trip through the gifts of many friends and family. Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support at 80%!</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:46:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-80/</guid>
      <description>After posting online, God used the generosity of donors to bring my funding for Ireland from 45% to 80% in a matter of days. I am so very grateful to all who have donated and all who are praying for the rest of the funds to come in and for the trip to have success.
I have also made some good contacts in Ireland and have a better idea of when and where I will be meeting with folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Update - April</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 17:42:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/support-update-45/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the generosity of many people, I&amp;rsquo;m 45.86% funded! Praise the Lord for his goodness. Will you join me in praying for God to provide the $2,003 still needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Partnership</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 15:01:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/finances/</guid>
      <description>By supporting Christian workers who go out “for the sake of the name,” you become a “fellow worker for the truth” (3 John 7–8). The cost of my trip is $3,700. This is a small amount if 100 of us share the cost. I’ve already invested my $37. Would you consider joining me by investing $37 or more to support our gospel work in Ireland? You can give online at http://bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Support</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 15:00:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/prayer/</guid>
      <description>I encourage you to pray Colossians 1:9–12 over our team. Pray that knowledge of the will of God would guide our team in all we say and do (1:9). Pray that we may walk worthy of the Lord and so: (1) bear fruit in good works (1:10a); (2) increase in the knowledge of God (1:10b); (3) be strengthened for endurance and patience (1:11); and (4) give joyful thanks to God (1:12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasuring Christ In Ireland 2017</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 17:05:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/ireland/</guid>
      <description>This June, I am traveling with the Bethlehem Baptist Church choir to proclaim the name of Jesus in Ireland. I will provide pastoral leadership for our team, deliver gospel teachings, and meet with Irish church leaders, missionaries, and planters.
Ireland is a land of remarkable beauty and history. The Irish people are welcoming and warm hearted. Yet, for all the beauty and cultural richness, Ireland is a land of deep suffering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner With Us</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:19:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/partner/</guid>
      <description>We are blessed and thankful for your desire to partner with us as we obey God’s call on our lives. You can partner with us in the following ways.
Pray for and with us This is by far the most significant way you can partner with us during this time. We serve a sovereign and good God who know’s our needs and desires before we ask him and works all things for our good and His Glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why BCS?</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/why-bcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:18:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/why-bcs/</guid>
      <description>I am grateful to the Lord for allowing me to set aside time for focused and intensive study into His Word and for the Godly men I will be learning from at Bethlehem College and Seminary. As Nicole and I prayerfully considered which seminary would best prepare me for future ministry, BCS was distinctive in several key areas.
 Church Embedded - BCS is tightly integrated with the daily life of Bethlehem Baptist Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Story</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:07:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/pages/pending/story/</guid>
      <description>Nicole and I met in middle school through a mutual friend. We lived in different cities, but often visited each other. We steadily grew in our friendship and eventually married the summer after graduation from High School. During the early years of our marriage, Nicole worked at Taste of Seattle as a Baker and I went to school at Saint Cloud State University for a B.S. in Special Education. Our dream was to start a family and in 2006 we had our first child, Malachi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>