<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Mykkanens</title>
    <link>http://themykkanens.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Mykkanens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 22:24:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://themykkanens.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 22:24:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a first post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasuring Christ In Ireland 2017</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 17:05:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/ireland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[coming soon]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner With Us</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:19:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/partner/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are blessed and thankful for your desire to partner with us as we obey God’s call on our lives. You can partner with us in the following ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pray-for-and-with-us&#34;&gt;Pray for and with us&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by far the most significant way you can partner with us during this time. We serve a sovereign and good God who know’s our needs and desires before we ask him and works all things for our good and His Glory. Yet he often chooses to perform that working through the prayers of His saints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pray for us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;- That study would kindle the fires of passion and love for God in my heart. That I would seek first to serve in my family, at school, at Bethlehem Baptist Church, and in the world. That Nicole would be comforted and strengthened as she transitions from the familiar to the unfamiliar. That Nicole would trust me and the goodness of Christ for daily grace. That the children would embrace the newness in their lives and turn to God who provides help in time of need. That the children would feel God’s love for them through us and through the church body.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pray with us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;- That the students and staff at BCS would serve one another in love as we grow together in knowledge and wisdom by the grace of God. That Bethlehem Baptist church would shine as a light for the gospel in the community of Minneapolis and God would provide opportunity for many to come to know Him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To stay up to date and learn specifics on what we are currently praying for ourselves and others, please subscribe to our newsletter below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;share-the-cost&#34;&gt;Share the cost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seminary is valuable training for pastors, but that training comes at a significant financial cost. BCS is distinctive in it’s low cost. Tuition at the school is subsidized heavily by individual and church donors. The tuition cost for a four year MDiv program is approximately $20,000 ($5,000/year). Tuition for comparable seminaries such as Southern Baptist Theological Seminary and Gordon-Conwell Theological Seminary averages $40,000 to $50,000. In addition to tuition are the costs of books and support materials as well as daily living expenses. Due to the significant class load required, I will only be able to work part time while attending. Nicole will also be re-entering the workforce during this time. We are grateful that God has given us the ability to work and are confident that He will provide for our needs and enable us to be content in whatever state we find ourselves in. We can do all things through Him who gives us strength. We will gladly pay the cost to serve our Lord. If God has blessed you with more than you need and you feel a desire to share this cost with us, you can do so in the following ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuition&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;- BCS incorporates the ability for donors to pay directly to the institution. You can do so by following &lt;a href=&#34;https://bcs.populiweb.com/bookstore/student_charges.php?accessKey=33164a7446641ccbe330e5d889287d5c223faa1b7633cb0fd68006211b3dab05485dd190341b2b733a26de4086a72d1debfba319b8e9ac3bad6c&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living Expenses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - Every amount given towards living expenses reduces the amount of hours Nicole and I need to work and frees us up for more time spent in direct ministry work, family time, or study. &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Textbooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - If you would like to help with textbook costs directly, use &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/w/FJ76CNTVQOXH&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; (will be updated each semester). &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why BCS?</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/why-bcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:18:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/why-bcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/86415622&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to the Lord for allowing me to set aside time for focused and intensive study into His Word and for the Godly men I will be learning from at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethlehemcollegeandseminary.org&#34;&gt;Bethlehem College and Seminary&lt;/a&gt;. As Nicole and I prayerfully considered which seminary would best prepare me for future ministry, BCS was distinctive in several key areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Church Embedded&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - BCS is tightly integrated with the daily life of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hopeingod.org/&#34;&gt;Bethlehem Baptist Church&lt;/a&gt;. The seminary was started by the church and seminarians serve within the church as part of the church body. This keeps the learning in classes directly linked to serving the body of Christ and helps us to remember that the purpose of this time of training goes beyond academic knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cohort Based&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - BCS accepts a limited number of seminary students each year (usually around 15). The men I will be taking classes with and ministering with and learning from will be together for the next four years. Our course load is also identical. This promotes discussions, debates, and encouragements to come from the depth of relationships built over time and through shared experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academically &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Rigorous&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;- Expectations for academic excellence are high. Greek and Hebrew language classes are held throughout the course of the four years. We will be taught to think deeply about what God’s Word says and to apply it with passion to our lives and the lives of those around us. We will also be examining  the history of the church and the saint who have gone before us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mentorship Emphasis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - I have been significantly impacted in my life by the mentoring of several men over the years. BCS emphasizes the importance of mentorship, referring to seminary students as “apprentices” and assigning us pastoral mentors. We can learn from these men who have many years of wisdom and ministry experience. We will also be engaged in mentoring students attending BCS at the undergraduate level to build our skill and experience in discipling others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Advantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; - Nicole and I desire to remain out of debt throughout seminary and thereafter in order to improve opportunities for ministry. We wish to be free to minister wherever God would call us without the need to consider how to pay off student loans. BCS is very affordable compared to many other top seminaries. For more information on financial matters, please visit the partner with us page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Story</title>
      <link>http://themykkanens.com/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 09:07:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://themykkanens.com/story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicole and I met in middle school through a mutual friend. We lived in different cities, but often visited each other. We steadily grew in our friendship and eventually married the summer after graduation from High School. During the early years of our marriage, Nicole worked at Taste of Seattle as a Baker and I went to school at Saint Cloud State University for a B.S. in Special Education. Our dream was to start a family and in 2006 we had our first child, Malachi. I began teaching in the public school system and Nicole stayed at home to take care of Malachi. In 2007, we welcomed Ruby to our family and in 2009 we welcomed Eleanora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicole and I envisioned our future as being very similar to our situation at the time. We had no desire to move from the Saint Cloud area. We were very involved in the life of our church and considered them our family. I was planning to teach for 30+ years and then retire. Into this preconception, God started to bring a different vision for our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly before our marriage, I began attending Communion Life Fellowship. Nicole grew up in this church and the pastor, Harold Wiehoff, gave us pre-marriage counseling. The church was smaller than the one’s I grew up in and the theology was different. Harold focused on expositional teaching from scripture and heavily emphasized God’s sovereignty and grace. This was a period of growth for Nicole and I relationally and spiritually as we examined together the doctrines of grace and started to form a deeper understanding of what the Bible says about our sin, God’s holiness, Christ’s redemption, and our calling as people saved by His grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God began stirring my heart with increased love for the local church and an increasing desire to serve the people in the church. The desire was small at first, but steadily grew as I became more involved relationally in the body and found opportunities to serve others and share the love of Christ with them. At the same time, God was growing Nicole’s ability and desire to speak the truth in love to other mothers through involvement in MOPS and Saint Cloud MOMS Club. We became more certain of a call to increased ministry in the church, but remained unsure of what form that ministry would take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through prayer and council from wise friends and family, our general sense of call progressed to a specific call to vocational pastoral ministry for me. As this call solidified, God put us through a period of waiting over several years. I continued to teach school and we focused on growing in our marriage, as parents, and in our maturity in Christ through involvement with our family at Communion Life Fellowship. As we explored options to pursue my sense of call, we were increasingly convinced of the benefit setting aside time for formal seminary training would bring. With prayer and counsel, we determined to sell our home and apply to seminary. We were accepted to Bethlehem College and Seminary in Minneapolis, MN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to now. We are excited to embark on this new journey. We are eager to see how God will grow us in this new stage in life and to be further prepared for serving His church for His glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the benefits of seminary as well as why we chose Bethlehem College and Seminary on the Why BCS? page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>